Very happy to end it off
with a bang here with Andrew.
So he's a research scientist
at Meta's GenAI team,
focusing on media generation.
Over the past few
years, his team
has focused on publishing
research papers that
push the frontiers of
video generative models,
including Emu Video
as well as Movie Gen.
Prior to working on Meta,
Andrew completed his PhD
at Oxford's Visual
Geometry Group,
VGG, under the supervision of
Professor Andrew Zisserman.
So without further ado,
I'll hand it off to Andrew
to take it.
Yeah, thank you for that.
Like the intro said,
I'm Andrew Brown.
I'm a researcher
in GenAI at Meta.
If you guys haven't
heard of that,
GenAI is the
research organization
that releases Meta's
generative models, things
like Llama for the text LLMs
and our media generation models
as well.
I've been there for about
two-and-a-half years,
ever since I finished my PhD.
And like Stephen said,
over that period,
we've released a bunch
of frontier pushing
video generation models.
So thank you so much
for inviting me.
I'm very honored.
Thank you.
And today's talk is transformers
for video generation.
So I saw in the list of
seminar speakers, already
you've had a bunch on NLP and
some media generation stuff.
I hope this is new, compared
to what you've heard already.
So text-to-video models.
You guys might have seen videos
like this on the internet.
But given a text prompt,
contemporary text-to-video
generation models can now create
these incredibly high-quality
videos.
Complex motion, fantastical
scenes, very high quality.
These things are amazing.
Another example I
quite like-- this
is a ghost in a white sheet.
These things are amazing.
And not only are they
super high quality,
they seem to have learned some
notion of the laws of physics.
The thing I like about this
one is if you look closely, you
can see the reflection of the
ghost is shown in the mirror
there.
So these models have clearly
learned something very--
like I was saying, if
you look very closely,
you can see this reflection
of the ghost in the mirror.
These things are amazing.
And it doesn't stop there.
So these text-to-video
generation models
can be used for other
amazing capabilities
as well, like editing.
So for example, you can give
these models an input video,
like on the top left, and
specify some edit prompts,
like turn the runner into
an inflatable dinosaur
or turn it into a cactus desert.
These things are amazing.
Now, I don't how
long a lot of you
have been paying attention
to the media generation field
or even the machine
learning field.
But if you've been only paying
attention for the last year
or year-and-a-half, this
is all that you're used to.
You're only used to seeing
generated videos that
are completely indistinguishable
from real ones.
But this is an incredibly
recent development.
So on the right here, I have
the same video I showed you
on the first slide.
This is from a model that
was released in October 2024.
And on the left, I have what
was an amazing state of the art
approach from September 2022.
This is another model that
was released by my team.
And I can't stress enough how
amazing this was at the time.
And this gap, you'll
see, is two years.
I'm sure every speaker at this
seminar has come in and said,
there's been amazing progress in
this machine learning subfield
with that one.
And there has been everywhere.
But nowhere is it more
clear than video generation.
So how did this happen?
This is what the subject of
today's talk is going to be.
How do we train models to
generate videos like this?
So all of the videos you saw
in the previous slides are
from a paper we
released in October 2024
called Movie Gen.
Here's a little snapshot
of the abstracts.
A little spoiler for how
we did this and a spoiler
for why I was invited
to this is that we
did it using transformers.
I saw this little guy
included in previous talks,
so I had to put him there.
So today's conclusions
are going to be twofold.
First, I'm going to talk you
through every detail of how
you train a transformer to
generate videos like this.
We publish all of the details.
We're going to step
through everything.
Some of the concepts are
going to be familiar,
things like transformers.
Some are going to be new.
We're going to go
through it all.
The second takeaway is going
to be this conclusion that I'll
keep on saying, that
throughout this project,
we learned that
scaling data, compute,
and model parameters
for a simple transformer
also works for video generation.
We've seen it work in all kinds
of machine learning fields.
We also saw it work here
for video generation.
So just a little bit
of personal background.
I think most of the
speakers that you've had
are from NLP, which makes
sense because transformers
came from NLP.
I'm a computer
vision researcher,
and I've been in visual
generation for a few years now.
And it hasn't always been
as popular as it is now.
So how I got into
this, I was sat
in this lecture hall in
the Engineering Department
at Oxford in, what, the
second year of my PhD.
And we were having a talk by
Professor Antonio Torralba
from MIT.
And he was presenting this
work called GAN Dissection.
Some of you may
have heard of GANs.
The state of the art image
generation approach at the time
were these generative
adversarial networks.
And in 2019, you could generate
a blurry face, or a blurry
kitchen, or a blurry bedroom.
And that was
amazing at the time.
And this paper here
was showing that you
could activate or deactivate
certain neurons in the GAN.
And in doing so, you could
make certain concepts
appear or disappear.
So these are the kind
of images that we
were generating at the time.
So this is like
a blurry kitchen.
And this was near
state of the art.
So you can see, the visual
concepts are pretty messed up.
It doesn't make a
huge amount of sense.
But I can't stress how
good this was at the time.
I'm sure a lot of you have seen
DALL-E, and Stable Diffusion,
and so on.
Things were not
always this good.
So the point of the paper,
or at least in this example,
was they were showing that you
could activate certain neurons
and make windows
appear in the kitchen.
You could imagine how your
kitchen would look with windows.
And the outcome was this.
So some pretty janky
windows on the left.
And my mind was completely
blown, as I can sense,
all of yours are as well.
This was amazing.
So what they showed here
is not only that the model
had learned a physically
plausible place
to put the windows.
But importantly, they'd also
shown that the model had
learned some notion of physics.
The model had learned that if
you put windows on the left hand
side of the room, light
will come through them,
and there'll be a reflection
off the marble countertop.
And you can see that here.
And the model had just learned
this by looking at images.
So this had a really
profound impact on me
as a young PhD student.
And I've been in visual
generation ever since.
So the body of the talk,
there's going to be five parts.
I'll give an
overview of the model
that we trained to talk about
architecture, data and training
recipe, results
and applications,
and a little discussion
on what is next.
So first, I included a
bit of historical context
on movie gen and
video generation.
Maybe some of you are quite new
to the video generation field.
The field is quite
new inherently.
This snapshot is maybe
three years from 2024,
back to around 2022.
This is a century in
machine learning research.
I haven't included
all of the works here.
There are some very relevant,
important works here.
I've just included a snapshot
to make a couple of points.
There have been two milestone
events in video generation.
The first was in 2022
when people started
using diffusion modeling.
This is when the whole community
started using diffusion.
That was a big step up in
visual quality at that point.
And the second one was in 2024.
And this is the point
of today's talk.
So before 2024,
people were using
quite small-scale
specialized architectures.
I say small because the
definition of small and large
has been moving all
over the place recently.
But these were
specialized architectures
for computer vision, things
like CNNs, units, and so on.
And then around 2024,
video generation
boarded this architecture
unification set up.
So all of the machine
learning fields,
we've seen people ditch
specialized architectures
and move towards this
simple transformer setup.
The reason is because all
of these different fields
are seeing the benefits of
efficiency and scalability
by moving to these transformers.
So in 2024, the video
generation community
started doing the same.
And that's where Movie Gen comes
in, which I'll talk about today.
So a quick overview
on what movie
is before we get
into the details.
So Movie Gen was a cast of
foundation models that generates
high-quality 1080p HD videos
with different aspect ratios
and synchronized audio.
Today, I'm just
going to be talking
about the text-to-video model.
I'll show some fun examples
later of the other models
that we trained.
And again, like I've been
saying, the point of the paper
was showing that scaling data,
training compute, and model
parameters for a simple
transformer trained
with flow matching--
I'll cover that later--
yielded state of
the art results.
We also presented a few
innovations and simplifications
along the way.
So Movie Gen Video, the
model, was a $30 billion
parameter foundation model
for joint text-to-image
and text-to-video generation.
The model was
trained on the order
of around 100 million videos
and one billion images.
So on to the architecture.
There are three main things
that I want to cover today.
The first is the representation.
What representation
are we learning?
The second is learning
objective that we use.
And the third is what
model architecture
we use for learning it?
If I do a good job here,
then all of you will all
there is to about
video generation.
I'm imagining most of you
have more of a NLP background
with text autoregressive models.
I'm going to try
and contextualize
all of this in relation to
text, and how it differs
from large language models.
So the representation.
What do we mean by that?
Well, we mean, how are
we going to represent
the data for the model?
We're doing generative
modeling here.
We're learning P of x.
The question here
is what should x be?
We know that x is going to be
derived in some way from videos,
but there's an open question
of how exactly do we do that?
So to motivate what
we ended up doing,
I'm just going to talk a
bit about the differences
between text and media.
So let's look at some
text data, for example.
And this piece of data, a
sentence, an image of a cat.
What has happened when this
data sample has been created
is a human has put in a
huge amount of thought
into compressing
what they're thinking
into this very well-designed,
semantically rich language.
It's very compressed.
Every word packs a huge
amount of information.
And it's also
inherently discrete.
So in practice, when people are
training large language models,
they can use a representation
that's quite close to this.
So they might use
a simple tokenizer
before feeding it
into the transformer.
Media data is incredibly
different to this.
So let's look at a
related piece of data,
an actual image of a cat.
No compression has
really occurred here.
This image is just
continuous raw data that's
been captured by your camera.
Maybe the only human effort
that's gone into this
is positioning the camera
and framing the cat
in the middle of the
camera, but nothing else.
As a result of this,
there's tons of redundancy.
So what I mean by this is if
you what a cat is, and then,
let's say, the
middle pixel you know
is this white fur on the cat.
Well, if you know
what a cat is, you
know the next pixel
along is probably
going to be white fur and
the next one along from that.
And if it's a video, you
know the same pixels,
one frame along, are also
going to be white cat fur.
There's a huge
amount of redundancy.
So this begs the question
of perhaps this raw data
could be transformed
into something that more
closely resembles language.
So what do we actually do?
So if you forget
everything that I just
said on the previous slide,
one thing you could do,
a very simple approach, is you
just model the pixels directly.
So let's say, you took
an image or a video,
you unraveled it into a
long sequence of pixels,
and then trained, let's say,
next token prediction on that.
And in a way, that's what
some prior works did.
Things like Imagen
Video or ImageGPT
back in the day, along with
a little bit of patching.
So this is a very
conceptually simple method,
but it's very
computationally constraining.
So the thing about
modeling pixels
directly is the number
of pixels scales
quadratically with the
image or video resolution.
It's bad for images.
It's even worse for video when
you have a temporal dimension.
In practice, what this means is
these models can only model very
low resolution images or videos,
things like 64-by-64 videos,
which is not ideal.
And if we want to generate
a actual large HD video,
these methods had to employ
a huge cascade of upsampling
stages.
Things super resolution models,
frame interpolation models
to increase the
size of the data.
So this really isn't ideal.
So instead, what
prior work does is
they learn a compressed latent
representation using something
like a VAE or a VQ-VAE
trained offline.
This is what every text
image model or text video
model you've seen
on social media
has been doing for a long time.
The advantages here are twofold.
If you're modeling a compressed
version of your data,
then you can natively
model larger data.
We don't need to go
down to 64-by-64.
We can natively model
something bigger.
The other advantage
is that this offline
trained VAE or VQ-VAE can remove
some of the computational burden
from the language model.
For example, these
autoencoders could
handle the modeling of how
two separate blades of grass
differ from each other
in an image or a video.
And it can take that burden off
the downstream language model.
So that is what we do.
From an architecture,
we train something
called a temporal autoencoder
for spatial temporal video
compression.
This is basically just a
variational autoencoder.
How does this work?
Well, you take a video, you'll
feed it through the TAE encoder.
A VAE consists of an
encoder and a decoder.
After the encoder,
the representation
will be compressed,
and you end up
with this latent representation
at the bottleneck in the middle.
And this is the
representation that we're
going to use downstream.
How you train these
things is quite simple.
Some of you may
have seen it before.
You take your video.
You feed it through the encoder.
You get to the bottleneck
latent representation.
You then decode it
back to pixel space.
And you have a bunch of
losses between the output
and the input, things
like L1 losses,
adversarial losses, and so on.
So this representation
in the middle
is what we're going to model.
When we talk about
learning P of x,
we're learning the
distribution of this latent.
What this means is when we train
a generative model on this,
it generates in this space.
It doesn't generate
an RGB space.
So after we generate
a video, we then
need to decode it
back to RGB space.
So the TAE that we trained
had 8x compression in each
dimension--
8x in height, width, and time.
And this was pretty high
compression at the time.
It's not the highest
compression anymore.
This was published
like six months ago.
And six months is, again, like
a decade in machine learning
research.
But at the time, this was
very high compression.
And like I said, this means
that we can natively model
very high-resolution videos.
As an example, the largest video
that we model in this work is
768-by-768 pixels,
16 seconds, 16 FPS.
Now, if we were to
model pixels directly,
and we took a video of that
size, we unraveled everything,
we treated one
pixel as one token,
and we flattened
the whole thing,
it would result in
150 million tokens.
Even with very long
contact training methods
with language models.
At the moment, this is
completely unfeasible.
But using this
temporal autoencoder,
the same video is just
compressed to 73,000 tokens.
So this is suddenly completely
computationally feasible
using today's
parallelism approaches,
today's infrastructure.
If anyone is doing
this maths offline,
there is also a
patch of high layer--
if someone thinks my
maths is wrong here.
So that's everything
for the presentation.
Does anyone have any
questions at this point?
[INAUDIBLE]?
No.
It's a great point.
A lot of autoencoders for
videos do use causality.
Some nice outcomes
of that is that when
you encode images that can be
encoded completely independently
of subsequent frames and so on.
But no, this isn't causal.
So next up, which generative
modeling learning objective
do we use?
So probably in most of the
talks that you've had so far,
you've heard about
autoregression
and next token
prediction for text.
In media generation,
we haven't been doing
that for a couple of years.
So the de facto approach
in most media generation
has been using
diffusion modeling.
We use something
called flow matching.
So what is flow matching?
Flow matching is, in a way,
a simpler generalization
of diffusion.
Now, if any of you have watched
a talk on diffusion modeling
or read anything about
diffusion or flow matching,
I'm sure you've seen a
figure like this before.
I'm going to give a
brief explainer of what
is similar between flow
matching and diffusion.
And then we're going to go over
what a training step looks like.
So both diffusion
and flow matching
have a very similar
setup, so you
assume that you have some
unknown data distribution.
This is the distribution
of images in this figure.
In this case, like
images of cats.
This is the distribution
you're trying to learn.
that we want
to learn and then sample from.
You also assume you have a known
data distribution on the right.
And we model this as normally
just like Gaussian noise.
Both assume then that we have
this fixed forward process.
What this means is
we have a method
of translating between
the unknown data
distribution and the known one
by iteratively adding noise.
Both assume that if you
keep on adding noise,
you basically end up at this
known data distribution.
Then, both of them
train a neural network
to do the reverse process.
So they train a neural network
to take one of these images
and iteratively denoise it.
And then at inference
time, you can iteratively
use this neural network
to go from a sample that's
pure noise back to a sample
from this data distribution
that you've just learned.
And that's how we end up
sampling images and videos.
So diffusion and
flow matching are
very similar in a lot of ways.
Flow matching is, in a way,
a simpler generalization.
It's been very recently
shown to result
in more robust training and more
efficient probability paths that
are easier and faster
to sample from.
So this paper came out
pretty recently in 2023
from some colleagues at Meta.
Importantly, it's been shown
to work better than diffusion.
And I'm not going to go into
a huge amount of detail here,
but we're going to go over how
a training step looks like.
So there are lots
of equations here.
We're going to step
through them pretty easily.
It's a three-step process.
We first take a training
data sample, X1.
This is your image of a
cat on the previous slide.
This is just an image
from your data set.
We then sample a time step.
This is a float
between zero and one.
And we sample from the
known data distribution.
This just means taking a
sample from a normal Gaussian.
We then construct a
training, sample Xt.
What is this?
This just intermediatte image,
a somewhat noisy image of a cat.
There are lots of different
ways of constructing Xt.
We use what's called the
simple linear interpolation
from the flow matching paper.
And the equation is shown here.
So this is how we
go from the three
things we sampled above to this
intermediate training sample.
Then, in flow
matching, what you do
is you train the model
to predict the velocity.
This is a value, which
moves the training,
sample back in the direction
of the data sample.
In actuality, it's very simple.
So this is how we compute
the velocity, simply
by differentiating
the equation above.
This is how we get
our ground truth.
And then on the right, we have
our actual learning objective.
So this is the
mean squared error
between the model prediction
and the ground truth velocity.
Here, the model prediction
is parametrized by u.
It takes as input
the training sample.
It's conditioned on two things.
It's conditioned on the text
prompt, that's P. Remember,
we're doing
text-to-video generation.
So we need to condition the
generation on the text prompt.
I'll cover later how we do this.
You condition on the
time step as well.
And then theta are
the model parameters.
You know know to
do flow matching.
Inference is also pretty simple.
So you start by sampling from
this known data distribution
Gaussian noise.
And then we use an ordinary
differential equation solver
to go back to the data
distribution, given
a series of time steps.
So very simply, you'll
sample some noise.
You'll sample a
stream of time steps.
At each time step, you
compute the model's prediction
for the velocity.
And you use the solver
to move the sample
in the direction of the
unknown data distribution.
And at the end of that,
you have your sample.
Low-level detail, we use
a quite simple solver.
There are lots of different
options you can choose.
So lastly, which model
architecture do we use?
Now, I already said that
we're using transformers.
The big goal of this paper was
to benefit from, like I said,
about seven times already,
scaling data, training compute,
and model parameters
with transformers.
But there is a question about
which transformer to use.
So in my research
organization, we
train these things
called Llamas.
Llama is the large language
model that Meta open sources.
We take the Llama 3 model, hence
why I pasted this L3 on it.
Llama 3 is quite a classic
dense, fully connected,
decoder-only language model.
So what we did in Movie Gen
is, you take your videos,
you encode them with the TAE
that we discussed earlier.
You flatten the tokens.
This gives you your
input sequence.
And we just throw it into Llama.
So very, very simple.
Now, when I say Llama I don't
mean a pre-trained Llama.
I don't mean one that's
been trained for text.
What I mean is the architecture.
So a randomly
initialized architecture.
But this is still
very important.
Training large language
models at scale
is incredibly
difficult. Every time
you change anything
about the architecture,
you need different
hyperparameters,
they scale differently.
It's incredibly tricky.
So the fact that we already,
in our research organization,
how to scale this
architecture, and the fact
that we have the
infra set up already
to train these things at
scale makes a huge difference.
So that's why the simplest
thing for us to do
was to go with the
Llama architecture.
Question.
So did you ever try taking an
initial or a pre-trained Llama?
We didn't do that
for this project,
but I agree that would be
a really cool thing to try.
It's not entirely clear
why that would work.
Obviously, these are very
different modalities,
different learning objectives.
But in a lot of
ways, there's a lot
of shared structure between
these modalities that
would maybe benefit from that.
So that last slide was very
deceptively oversimplified.
There are some changes that
we needed to make to Llama 3.
So importantly, Llama 3 is a
model for autoregressive text
generation.
And we are doing text-to-video
generation using flow matching.
So there are three changes
that we need to make.
I'm going to go over
all of them exhaustively
to hammer the point that we
barely changed the architecture.
The first thing
that we need to do
is incorporate the
text conditioning.
You'll have seen on
the previous slide
that our input sequence is
just made up of video tokens.
We're doing
text-to-video generation,
so we need to incorporate the
text conditioning somehow.
And we do this using
cross-attention layers.
So very simply, we
construct a sequence made up
of our text conditioning, and
we add cross-attention layers
into the transformer block.
So these go between the
self-attention layers
and the feedforward network.
It's a very common way of
adding text conditioning
for media generation models.
There is a question as well
of what should your text
representation be?
How should you
construct this sequence?
One very simple
thing to do would
be you just tokenize the
prompt, the caption, and then
you feed that in.
But when you do that,
you're very much
burdening your model
with learning this text
representation from scratch.
So instead, we use pre-trained
text representations.
We use three, in fact--
three that are
complementary to each other.
The first two-- all of them are
pre-trained frozen text models
basically.
The first two have very
semantic level representations.
UL2 is a large scale
encoder/decoder model.
MetaCLIP is our
internal CLIP model.
And the third one has more
of a character level text
representation by T5.
So we encode the text prompt
using all three of these,
we project them all to the model
dimension, and we concatenate.
And that gives us
our text sequence.
The second thing we
need to do-- you'll
remember from the
learning objective
that we also need to
condition on the time step.
So what do we do here is, we
do this in adaptive layer norm
blocks.
So we've already added
a cross-attention block.
We also add this adaptive
layer norm block.
This might seem like
quite a strange way
of adding some conditioning.
It's something that was
popularized in the Diffusion
Transformer paper, which was the
first paper that used diffusion
with transformers--
obviously, by the name.
It might seem a
little bit random.
It's basically very
computationally cheap
and works super well.
Number 3-- there
are only three--
we use full
bidirectional attention.
Llama is an
autoregressive text model
that use causal masking
for next token prediction.
For the flow matching objective,
we have no such constraints.
We want every video token to
see every other video token.
We don't care about causal
masking, so we take that out.
A very low level detail is
that because of this, we
use multi-head attention instead
of grouped query attention.
But that's everything.
Other than that, it's
the Llama architecture.
So we now have our full
architecture diagram.
I was very wary of putting
this earlier because it's
pretty complicated, but
I think it should all
make sense at this point.
So from left to right,
during training,
we take one of our
training videos.
We encode it with the TAE to
get to our compressed latent
representation.
It goes through
a small patchify.
This is just does some
extra compression.
And we flatten it, and that's
how we get our input sequence.
During training, we'll
construct our training, sample
by combining it with
this Gaussian noise.
During inference,
this whole sequence
will start off being
Gaussian noise.
The sequence goes through
these Llama transformer blocks.
We add in the conditioning, and
then we get our output sequence.
During training, we compute
our loss and backpropagate.
During inference, we would do
this iterative denoising process
and finally decode
back to the RGB space.
Any questions on
the architecture?
Question about inputs.
So you start off
with Gaussian noise
and then you have a sequence
of denoising steps [INAUDIBLE].
But where does the
text prompt go?
Why doesn't it generate a
random video [INAUDIBLE]?
So at inference, for
a given text prompt,
we add this conditioning
into the model always.
So the input sequence
is just Gaussian noise.
But that's not what the
text information comes in.
The text information
comes in through
these cross-attention layers.
So even though the input
sequence is just noise,
the model is still seeing
these clean text information.
We don't noise the text
or anything like that.
Does that make--
does that make sense?
Two questions.
One, I noticed this segment
[INAUDIBLE] in the equations,
that you don't see noise
all the way to clean data.
Does that mean-- is that
segmentation making sure
that you always get diversity in
the same query every single time
you go through the
denoising process?
You actually go all
the way to pdata.
It's just a hyperparameter
that we keep constant.
I cannot remember off the top
of my head exactly what that
hyperparameter is for, actually.
I'm going to talk to
you about that after.
The other question is, how many
denoising steps is typically
required?
So it's a very good point.
So during inference, you'll
sample a series of time steps.
Usually, with these flow-based
models, the more you sample,
the better you'll better
approximate these probability
paths.
In practice, we use 250--
I think.
One of the advantages
of flow matching
is that the probability paths
are theoretically straighter.
So you should be able to require
less function evaluations
to approximate this path.
That's one of the advantages.
Is that 250 like--
so there's not a pre-described
number of TAEs during training?
Yeah, that's continuous.
But during inference, we just
sample some discrete ones.
So I have a general
question on the two videos
that you showed the difference
between 2022 and 2024.
Was the improvement
just algorithmic,
or did you also improve the hard
work in terms of better GPUs,
or it was just a pure
algorithm improvement?
So I think everything
comes down to scale.
There are quite a lot of
things that have changed.
There's an architecture change
moving towards transformers,
and then there's the
scale, and that includes
a whole load of things.
Scaling the data scaling
the amount of compute
in order for that to
be like tractable.
Better GPU hardware does help.
There wasn't a huge
improvement in GPU hardware
over those two years.
It might have been one or two
generations of NVIDIA's stuff.
So now, we have an
architecture that we're
pretty confident scales.
We have a learning
objective that we think
should work in flow matching.
That's pretty much
it for the details.
It's not the entire story,
but that's a lot of it.
So the last technical details
are about data and the training
recipe.
So data.
I think in a lot of ways, this
is the most important slide
of the entire talk today.
Data is so important for
training large language models.
And by the way, when I
say large language models,
I'm just talking
about transformers
at scale for any modality.
People use different
definitions there.
But these models are
incredibly data hungry.
They require
internet scale data,
and they require the
data to be clean.
The scaling laws depend
on the data being cleaned.
Otherwise, the scaling
laws don't hold.
And the model output
quality depends
on the data being cleaned.
As a result of this, research
groups at these big companies
spend a huge amount
of resources on data.
This is something that I
find isn't really talked
about so much.
But they'll spend huge amounts
of resources in terms of GPUs
and also actual researchers.
Often, on these research
teams, the data teams massively
outnumber the
modeling teams, which
was something very new to
me after my little PhD.
So why is this?
Well, remember we're
training generative models.
We are learning this
distribution of our training
data, and then we're
sampling videos from it
that are likely according
to that training data.
So if we want to sample
the kinds of videos
that I showed you in
the first two slides,
then all of our training
data needs to look like that.
I'm mainly talking
about pre-training here.
You obviously have a
post-training phase as well,
where you can align your videos
to be more high quality perhaps.
But you're pre-training data
still needs to look great.
So this is a huge challenge.
We train the model on the order
of around 100 million videos.
How do we get to this number?
Well, we can predict
a training budget
that we had for this project.
And you want as many
videos as you can.
You don't epoch very much.
So the challenge was how to
get this many videos that
are high enough quality.
At the time of Movie
Gen, we constructed
this incredibly detailed,
complex pipeline
with a bunch of handcrafted
and model-based filters.
I'll just talk through
a few bits of it
because of the sheer amount
of work that went into this.
So you start with a large pool
of videos from some corpus.
They may be different lengths,
long tail of concepts.
We did a bunch of visual
filtering on these--
removing videos that are
too small, scene changes,
bad aesthetics.
We removed a bunch of
videos that have bad motion.
It turns out a bunch of
videos in any large corpus
have really slow motion,
janky motion, motion effects.
We removed all of those.
We then did a content
filtering step.
This is first deduplication, but
the really important one here
is resampling.
Large language models
do not work well
when they're trained on a
very imbalanced data set
in terms of concepts.
So something with
a very long tail.
They work best if the concept
distribution is roughly, roughly
uniform.
And that uniformity
doesn't occur if you just
take a random set of videos.
So we do this very complex
visual concept extraction,
clustering.
We upweight certain clusters,
downweight certain clusters.
All of this will give
us a set of videos.
We also need captions
because we're
doing text-to-video generation.
And we generate these
automatically using Llama 3.
So that is data.
Very lastly, the
training recipe.
So this multi-stage
recipe here was optimized
for convergence speed.
We start off with a 256 pixel
T2I stage image generation.
Here, are the model can whip
through a bunch of samples
in very few
relatively GPU hours.
We then move on to a
pre-training stage with joint
text-to-image and
text-to-video generation,
where we progressively increase
the resolution from two 256p
to 768p.
At the highest
resolution here, 768p,
that's where we have the
sequence length of 73K.
And we trained this on 6,000
GPUs around 1,500 batch size.
At this point, the
model splinters.
So we have a text-to-video
post-training stage.
This is just SFT on a very small
set of very high-quality videos.
And then we also branch off into
these different capabilities.
I'm not going to talk
about those a bunch,
but I'll show you
some examples later.
Any questions?
Sure.
A wider tailed
data set of videos.
Is there pre-training
you can do specifically
to address those
kinds of challenges?
Yeah.
I think-- definitely.
I guess the question is
about certain concepts
in your pre-training data.
I guess, in a very large
corpus we'll be training on,
there's an incredibly
long tail of concepts.
Pretty much every concept that
you might want to generate
would probably appear at
some point in that data set.
Anything else?
So lastly, the results
and applications.
So putting everything together
that I just showed you--
and that's all of the
technical details, by the way--
we published all of this--
we get videos like
this and the ones
that I showed at the
beginning of the talk as well.
And this pretty much sums up
the whole point of this project.
I really want to hammer home
that these kinds of videos
were nowhere near
possible before people
started scaling transformers.
And we showed here that, again,
this classic architecture
unification story, scaling data
model parameters and compute
for a simple
transformer, ended up
in a model that can reason about
objects, motion, and physics
just by watching videos.
So none of this was possible,
and it's scaling transformers
that unlocks all of this.
I have to keep on
pressing replay
because I couldn't figure
out how to do auto-replay
on Google Slides.
How many PhDs does it
take to auto-replay?
So another one.
Here's a sloth with pink
sunglasses on a donut float.
Again, I think the physics of
sloth-like donut flirtation
here are good.
This slide isn't only a joke.
It does actually highlight
something quite important.
When we're training
generative models,
one important thing
is how well it
generalizes to concepts
that maybe weren't
in its pre-training data.
We can't be sure that there
are no sloths in floats
in the pre-training data.
But by common sense, there
probably aren't too many.
So the fact that it
can generate this
is testament to its
generalizing capabilities.
A few other things.
I showed you some of
these at the beginning.
We also trained a
Movie Gen edit model.
Like I said before, you take the
original video on the top left
and you can provide these
precise edit instructions.
This is really magic to me.
I didn't get a chance to
cover this too much today,
but the team trained
this with paired data.
It's incredibly hard
to get paired data
for this task-- these
pairs of input and outputs.
They came up with a fascinating
self-supervised approach
for this.
I'd really recommend
reading the paper.
Where did you guys get the
data from on this project?
The videos are completely
licensed videos by Masha.
And one more example here.
You can take-- everyone wants
to take a video of their penguin
and put some Victorian
outfits on it.
So this is great.
One other model that we trained
is the personalization model.
So here, this is
Movie Gen video.
But with the added
capability, you
can condition on an
image of yourself.
So here, the model can
generate a video that
is faithful to the text prompt,
but also contains the person
in the conditioning image.
So that's really fun.
And another funny example here.
This is my colleague that I
worked on the project with.
This makes me laugh.
So if anyone is interested in
this, please go read the paper.
A bunch of work went into this.
Very lastly, we're going to see
now if the theater has audio.
It doesn't.
So we trained this
Movie Gen audio model.
Again, I didn't have time
to go into this today.
But this is a model that will
condition on text and a video,
either real or generated, and
generate synchronized audio.
So this way, we can add audio
to our generated videos.
It's an amazing research
team that did this.
So I'd recommend going
to check out the paper
if you're interested.
So there are a couple
of just points left.
Firstly, some
quantitative results.
It's incredibly hard to do fair
comparisons in video generation.
We don't have automated
metrics or anything like this.
So what we did was, we did a
very extensive human evaluation
study.
We came up with a
bunch of metrics
that are somewhat orthogonal
to each other that
test every aspect of video
generation, things like motion
quality, how well the videos
follow, the text prompts,
visual quality.
These metrics are
shown on the left.
I won't go into a huge
bunch of detail here,
but they're very fully
defined in the paper.
We put in a load of work to make
sure that the human evaluators
had low standard deviation when
multiple evaluators were rating
the same thing.
So we compared to all
of the methods that
were released in the same year.
This is 2024.
So things like runways models,
Luma, Sora at the time,
and KLING.
And these are net win
rates you're seeing here.
So a score above zero means
that our model was preferred.
At the time of
release, Movie Gen
outperformed all
of the prior work.
So that's great.
It's very hard to
draw conclusions here.
The one conclusion
we can draw is
that Movie Gen was better than
these at the time of release.
Like researchers,
what we like to do
at this point is
to look into all
of the technical reports
of the prior work
and see what they
did differently,
and what did Movie
Gen do differently?
Because we'd like to conclude--
what led to these improvements?
Was it more compute?
Was it flow matching?
Was it better data filtration?
Things like that.
But it's, unfortunately,
not possible in today's age
to do that because we don't
see research publications.
But what we do know is that
all of the technical details
I just presented work, and
they work really, really well.
And they're a good
starting point for anyone
who's looking to improve
text-to-video generation.
And we hope the community does.
The very last technical
thing, scaling laws.
I've talked throughout
the whole talk
today about architecture
unification across modalities
and learning
objectives, and this
was a really nice result that we
found at the end of the project.
So what you're seeing here
is a scaling law graph.
How we use these when we're
training large language models
is often when you start
training like a GPT, or a Llama,
or whatever, you have a
certain training budget.
This is how many months
you have and how many
GPUs you have for that period.
But if you know that
training compute budget,
an open question is how
big your model should be.
What should be the optimal model
size for that compute budget?
It could be a very small model.
You train for more--
you train for-- more
iterations or a larger model,
you train for less.
These scaling law curves are
for estimating the optimal model
size for a given compute budget.
So just looking at
the blue crosses,
we plotted a few of
these data points
for a Movie Gen. Remember,
Movie Gen, text-to-video model,
Llama 3 architecture.
And looking at the
blue crosses, we
can see this nice
correlation we often
see in scaling laws
with transformers.
We then overlaid the
Llama 3 scaling law.
So this is the scaling
law for the text model.
And amazingly, we see
that the Llama 3 scaling
law for this
text-only model serves
as a reasonable
predictor for model size
and compute for
video generation.
And this seems to hint that
scaling laws for transformers
are maybe modality independent,
which is pretty fascinating.
So we're on the last part now.
What is next?
Movie Gen did not
solve video generation.
There are still
lots of problems.
The model will struggle with
generating complex motions
from complex prompts.
An example here is
a dramatic scene
of two cars colliding
at an intersection.
So it's looking pretty
good at this point.
And then at some point
near the end, they--
I don't what you'd call that--
they independently implode.
At one point, the silver car
turns into two cars as well.
So this is a random
generation from our model.
So text-to-video
generation is not solved.
So my final slide is some
ideas about where I think
video generation is going next.
Things that I'm sure we'll
see some version of at some
point soon.
So what is next?
How can we solve the issues that
you saw in the previous slides?
Well, the first obvious one
is scaling everything more.
This has been like the
story of machine learning
for the last six
years or something.
And I think this
would definitely work.
Movie Gen was a $30
billion parameter model.
It was based on Llama 3.
The largest Llama
3 model was 405B.
I think scaling everything
more would definitely
result in far higher
quality generations.
Some challenges there would
be around scaling data
by an order of magnitude.
Number 2 is reasoning.
We've all seen the amazing
benefits in language modeling
that have come from reasoning
in the last year or two.
Here, the reasoning gives the
model the ability to pause,
think, generate a
chain of thoughts,
self-correct before
generating an answer.
I think it's very clear that
video generation models would
benefit from this kind of
reasoning capability as well.
I think that could
result in a step change.
When all of us were
looking at the videos
on the previous slide,
it was very clear
that something was wrong.
It looked very obvious to us.
It doesn't seem too
unfathomable to be
able to imbue some
video generation
model with the capability
to self-correct,
maybe see that there is
some errors in the video
that it generated
and correct it.
There are lots of really
interesting research questions
here.
Like what does it mean to
generate a reasoning trace
for media generation?
You might have seen these
chain of thoughts that
are generated by like R1 or R3.
I wonder what that looks
like for media generation.
The other issue
is how to verify.
So these latest state of
the art reasoning approaches
are all trained with RL.
RL requires verification
models to verify
the correctness of the outputs.
It's an open research
question, what that
means for a video generation.
How do you verify the
correctness of a video?
Very lastly, we have
native generation.
So recent large language
models are natively multimodal.
They can generate texts.
They can do image understanding.
They can do video understanding.
Some can even do
image generation.
So it's an interesting question
as to whether video generation
would also benefit from being
thrown into this native mix.
And if so, there are
interesting questions around how
you would train such a thing?
I've just talked you through
how flow matching seems to work
the best for video generation.
Is there a way that you can have
multiple learning objectives?
Do you need to unify
the learning objectives?
Things like that.
So very lastly,
it was a huge team
that worked on
Movie Gen. These are
a bunch of amazing researchers.
I had so much fun
on this project.
Learned so much.
There are loads of
good friends here.
So yeah, shout-outs
to all of them.
So I'm going to leave
it on this slide.
But we can do questions
now if there are any.
[APPLAUSE]
I guess especially given
[INAUDIBLE] is so involved.
And a lot of these
types of architectures
are unit-based with
that kind of structures.
And that-- so the actual
diffusion policy, surprisingly,
like the ConvNet
architecture outperforms
the transformer architecture for
action diffusion for robotics.
And they make an
argument that it
has an inductive
bias about smoothing,
so there's more
consistency in the spatial
and the time domain and
all that great stuff.
What did you say back
to that, I guess?
So I haven't read
that particular paper,
but it does sound
like a familiar point,
I guess the whole theory around
architectural unification
is that we might have
these specialized
architecture like CNNs, and
they hold these inductive biases
around visual data,
like they prioritize
these local interactions
with the convolutional mask,
and so on.
And the going idea
has been that when
you're training at small scale,
having these inductive biases
helps.
But when you're
training at large scale
and you have enough data, you
can learn all of these yourself
with a transformer in a
less constrained setting.
We have found that
scaling transformers here
works better than scaling
these specialized architectures
for a few reasons.
I mean, it's not
even to say that I
don't think CNN's could scale.
It seems as though it's
easier to scale transformers.
It's more
straightforward to know
in which direction to scale.
All the infrastructure
already exists.
But it's a very big debate.
I'm not like calling it.
Hey.
Can this modeling approach be
used for 3D generation to video
games and stuff like that?
So if you go back
to the architecture,
it's totally
modality independent.
So for any-- this is
for videos and images.
The important thing here is
that we've turned a modality
into a sequence of tokens.
At this point, after
that, everything
that's happening
in the architecture
is modality independent.
So really, for any new
kind of data, all you need
is a way of turning it
into a sequence of tokens.
It may be more challenging
to encode that kind of data.
But as long as you can
encode it, in some way,
to a series of tokens, you can
use the exact same approach.
We have a lot of
questions online as well.
So I can read a few
of those right now.
So one is, so 16 seconds seems
like the longest videos you can
effectively generate right now.
What are the main obstacles
or things keeping us
from getting to
longer, for example,
real movie-length generations?
So the main issue is
a computational one.
Well, there are so many
different answers to this.
If you're thinking from
the Movie Gen set up,
the issue is sequence length.
Given the level of
compression that we had,
73K was pretty much the longest
sequence length we could
feasibly train at.
If you want to train
on 32 second videos,
that's going to double.
There are multiple
ways around this.
You could train an encoder
with far more compression,
and then you could get
to videos that long.
There's another question
about learning objective.
Here, we generate
everything at once.
There are lots of
papers out there
that will iteratively generate
videos along the temporal axis.
You will generate a
chunk and then generate
a new chunk conditioned
on the previous trunk,
like next token prediction.
So I don't think
there's necessarily--
there are lots of
ways around it,
and there are lots
of interesting papers
that generate infinite
length videos using
these iterative processes.
Let me see.
There's some questions on
synthetic data compute.
So someone says, Meta
is a rare example
of having an abundance
of training data.
What if you run
out of video then?
What's next, I guess?
I really how to answer that.
If we run out of video--
look, I think there's--
I think that there's a
lot of interesting work
to be done on improving
the data filtration steps.
So in this slide,
we were optimizing
this for high precision.
So making sure that all
the videos at the end
were very high quality.
Recall was sacrificed
throughout this.
These are very
computer vision terms.
But we would have lost a lot
of good data in this very
complex pipeline here.
One way forward for
getting more data
is moving to smarter
ways of doing
this process, maybe completely
language model-based,
for example.
I think that's one answer.
A question about compute.
This is more general, I guess.
How can academic researchers
contribute to video generation
without having access
to thousands of GPUs?
It's obviously very
tough to do this level
of pre-training outside
of industry labs.
But throughout this paper, we've
used a bunch of innovations
that came from academia.
For example, a lot of
the flow matching work
was done at universities.
The main paper that we
take inspiration from
did come from Meta.
But this kind of research
can be done at small scale,
and then all of us
can learn from it.
The pre-training is very tough.
I think the
pre-training is tough.
But things like
learning objectives,
I think post-training
schemes, we've
seen a lot of great work coming
out of academia for that.
We've got a few questions,
all related to text, I guess.
Some folks are
saying, there's a lot
of work of cleaning and
processing video data.
How do you make sure that
the actual text, for example,
the Llama 3 generated captions,
are high quality and complete?
Good question.
We put a lot of work into
training this Llama 3
captioner, basically.
So this is a
video-conditioned Llama model.
This went through its
own large scale training
in order to generate
good-looking captions that were
aligned with what we wanted.
But certainly, there's a lot
of room for improvement there.
These captions are not as good
as human-written captions.
There are a lot of
architectural reasons for that.
A lot of these video-conditioned
language models cannot see
the whole video.
If it's a 16 second
video, it's 16 FPS.
Often, it's far too
much video for the model
to be conditioned on.
So often, with a lot of
these open source models,
not only Llama, but
Gemma and so on,
you have to subsample frames.
And so you're
blocking the model--
the language model from
seeing a lot of the video.
It's going to lead to some
issues, some missed things.
So we do our best by
training and post-training
a captioning model, doing a
bunch of evaluations on it.
But that's definitely
something that can be improved.
And there's a bunch of
really cool results out there
from the text-to-image
community,
showing that if you
improve captions,
your image quality gets better.
It's not entirely clear why,
but that keeps on happening.
Makes sense.
Someone asked a
related thing, which
is how much role or importance
does the text or prompt encoder
play?
I think there were some image
generation works, which showed
replacing the text encoder.
I think it was from CLIP to T5.
Really helped
improve performance.
Did you guys play around with
several different text encoders?
So this particular
series of text encodings
was precedent in our team.
We took motivation
from a recent state
of the art text-to-image
paper that used
this series of text encodings.
But it's worth pointing out
here that it is quite strange
what we've done here.
You would think it would
be intuitive that you
want your best possible
text representation here.
All of these text
representations
are nowhere near
state of the art.
They're not Llama,
they're not GPT.
There's been a few works and
empirical findings showing
that in this setup, at
least, decoder-only text
representations don't work
as well for some reason.
Some reasons for that could
be or have hypothesized
that you need a text
representation that is more
aligned with the media space.
That's why a lot of people
you'll see conditioning
on CLIP, which is what we do.
So a bunch of cool
work to do here.
We didn't ablate in
this project, though.
I have a question followed
up on the text part.
How well would this do
with very detailed prompts?
Like I want to move a video
about this person wearing
this specific color, and here's
what happens later on, and then
a very detailed script.
Rather than just a video
of some penguins, I guess.
We definitely did observe
that the model can
do these sequential actions,
but not always completely
accurately.
Some of that might be
issues in the captioning
of the pre-training data, like
are you accurately captioning
all of these things happening?
But that will be
one of the places
where it struggles if you were
to detail three or four things
happening in sequence.
We have one question, which
is, could you somehow hard code
in some priors
related to physics
and real-world common sense to
improve the realism and accuracy
of generated videos?
I guess that might be related to
that video of the car splitting
and all of that.
So in a way, it's like the
antithesis of the things
that we were trying
here, of removing
all of the inductive biases and
just scaling, compute, and data.
But I do think those are
interesting things to try.
Simply because maybe
if you are trying
to learn the laws
of physics better
in just random videos
from a large pool
aren't maybe the best
thing to use there.
There are other cool works
that have been released,
where they're trained entirely
on video game data, things
like that.
I think encoding
some of priors would
be cool because there
are certain things
about the natural world
that we do know for sure.
Something like computer
vision principles, and so on.
But yeah, we didn't
do that here.
Do you know how to
possibly encode those?
Yeah.
That's like a super
open question.
Super open question.
Makes sense.
We've got a couple
others online,
and then we can go
back to in-person.
One's more on deepfakes
and malicious use
of video generation models.
Is there any work on things like
watermarking to deal with that?
There's definitely a bunch
of work on watermarking.
of work on watermarking
coming from a few groups.
DeepMind has released a few
interesting papers on it.
NASA has a team working
on this as well.
So yeah, very important
work to be done.
I'll read one, and
then we can go back
to some in-person questions.
One's about GANs, actually.
I've noticed some older models
have a GAN discriminator
before or in the decoder
for temporal coherence.
Is this still useful or does
scale overcome this need?
They mean in the VAE decoder?
I think so.
So we also have a GAN
discriminator there.
It's not necessarily for
temporal consistency.
That might be one
of the outcomes.
There's a historical
precedent for this.
When you are training these--
where is it?
When you're training
these VAEs, folk
found-- it was the Stable
Diffusion researchers, actually,
while they were still
at college in Germany.
They published this paper called
VQGAN back in 2021, I think.
And they showed
that normally how
you train these VAEs
is that you just
use L1 losses between
the input and the output.
But they found that the amount
of compression you could do
was very limited when
you were doing that.
So what they started doing was
adding some adversarial losses
from the GAN literature.
What this does is
it tells the VAE
that I don't have to decode
exactly what was given to me.
Because the GAN losses,
they're not L1 losses.
They're not pixel-level losses.
These losses are
just how well the GAN
can tell if it's a real
image or a fake one.
So when folks started training
VAEs with these losses,
the outputs were given
a bit more freedom.
So the model could
generate a range
of things for a certain
input and it's not
getting penalized from the
loss as long as they look real.
And I realize there's a
bunch of detail there.
But basically, by
adding these losses,
we were able to get another
2x level of compression.
So we are also using
adversarial losses in the VAE
if that was their question.
Someone added an interesting
question just now,
which is, how might you
make sure all the videos
in your training data are real?
What if some of them are fake?
I guess that's
related to some work
nowadays in language models.
But once more and
more training data
becomes synthetically generated,
does that lead to any issues,
I guess?
Definitely this idea of data set
poisoning, it's often called,
is a problem.
I think there are a couple
interesting answers to this.
Firstly, in our pre-training
data, if it's low quality,
then we don't want
to train on it.
And hopefully, we would
find it and get rid of it.
But training on generated data
is not always a bad thing.
Most contemporary post-training
approaches for language models
are based upon training
on generated data.
You train on generations
from the model itself.
So it's not like training on
generated data is always bad.
If there's some really
bad generated videos
in the pre-training data, we
do want to get rid of those.
But it's not always bad.
We've got time for a couple
more in-person questions.
Can you share-- I
mean, I understand
that it will be
confidential-- but just to get
a sense of [? data ?]
structure that it took
to do the training as
well as a different time,
how big a company is or hosting
a single instance of the model?
How would you have a GPU,
GPUs to run every request?
Or if you can share those
just to get a sense of.
In the paper, we
included full details
of the training infrastructure.
That will be there.
I don't think we included any
details about the inference
of the structure of that.
There are lots of details
on the infra in the paper.
I would recommend
you to go there.
Any other questions?
I don't know if I missed
that, but for the videos,
you generated, do
they come with audio?
Yeah.
So this text-to-video
model that I've shown here,
it generates video.
But with the publication,
we released--
well, published about a--
where is it?
Actually, no, we're not going
over that problem again.
There's no audio.
[INAUDIBLE]
Yes.
So there were-- there was a
separate Movie Gen audio model
that we trained that will add
audio to a generated video.
[INAUDIBLE] the video
has two separate models,
and the audio is another
level of complexity, where
there are multiple tracks.
And if you want to train on MIDI
files for MP3, like [INAUDIBLE].
So what is the current progress
of this audio generation?
So we have a really
great audio research
team that works on this.
One very nice thing
to do, I think,
would be to generate everything
at once, like video and audio.
The two modalities
are very correlated.
There's a lot of
shared information.
So theoretically,
both modalities
should benefit from
being trained together.
The audio even encodes
some information
about videos that are
not present in the video.
The issue is one of data.
It's very hard to get
high-quality video data.
It's even harder to
get high-quality video
with good audio data.
So that's part of the
reason why we didn't
do that for this project.
Awesome.
Thanks so much, Andrew, for
the very insightful talk
and answering all our questions.
[APPLAUSE]